# **Andrew January**

Flat 2, 4 Lorne Street, Reading, Berkshire, RG1 7YN

Email andrewjanuary@gmail.com

Tel +447999408105

Skype aJanuary

## Objective

I have several years experience working in a professional software development environment. During that time I have been pivotal in improving the automated tests, as well as automating some of the more error prone and laborious tasks in the development lifecycle.

I am now looking to work at a company with a culture that values modern software development practices, such as test-driven development, so that I can focus on growing my skills as a developer and learning new technology alongside smart and motivated people.

I would also like to work on a new technology stack such as one built on Ruby.

#### Technical Skills

Programming Languages C# (7 years), Java (4 years), Ruby, Javascript, SQL, Python, Objective-C,

PHP, Delphi, Flex, TCL

Technologies and Libraries jQuery, JSON, HTML, XML, Sinatra, Apache Server, Tomcat, Ivy, Spring,

jUnit, Mockito

Operating Systems Windows (7 years), OS X (6 years), Linux (Slackware and Ubuntu, 6 years)

IDEs and Editors Vim, Eclipse, Visual Studio

Source Control Git, Subversion, CVS

## Experience

2012 - Present

#### Evertz Microsystems Ltd.

Software Developer

Evertz provides hardware and software to broadcasting companies worldwide to manage video media as well as scheduling and executing video playout.

In my current role I develop and maintain a Java based product called Mediator: an Apache Tomcat hosted application that exposes a Flex UI used by broadcast operators. It distributes the work among several servers as well as using an XY redundancy model to provide high availability.

I have been instrumental in several features and innovations:

- Wrote the implementation of the US government Emergency Alert System for the Public Broadcasting Service. A Java daemon receives national alerts and transforms them into a schedule of video events to show weather warnings and live Presidential broadcasts.
- Helped develop a hub-and-spoke model of redundancy, designing and implementing an XML based synchronisation protocol with timeouts and robustness against connectivity issues.
- Rewrote the Java and Delphi implementations of the in-house timecode mathematics library to increase precision and accuracy. I made careful consideration of backwards compatibility issues as it subtly changed the result of many previously incorrect calculations. I also refactored the test suite, drastically increasing coverage and removing many redundant tests.

- Introduced the dependency management tool Ivy into the development workflow, removing the need to manually manage dependencies and artifacts. I also created training material on Ivy for other developers.
- Implemented several extensions to the HTML/Javascript based configuration tool, including live previews of user-defined forms and the ability to resize and filter tables. This was done with a mix of Javascript, jQuery and modifications to the in-house annotation driven Java bean serializer/deserializer.
- Added automated unit testing to the configuration tool using Jasmine and PhantomJS, as well as a wrapper to allow it to be driven from the ant build tool and Eclipse.

#### 2010 – 2012 OpenBet Technologies Ltd.

Software Developer

OpenBet supplies online casino games to operators worldwide.

I developed the Java server-side logic for games, running on top of an Apache Tomcat Servlet that exposed an XML API to be consumed by third part front-ends.

I regularly worked through a large part of the software lifecycle, from design to implementation to support.

- Successfully developed a large number of games that were deployed on several customer's websites.
- Implemented two new game engines being used as the basis for games written by myself and other developers.
- Introduced the use of automated testing tools such as Cucumber's executable specifications to improve regression testing, reduce bugs and help ensure the specifications were met correctly.
- Wrote technical design documentation for dozens of games that were subsequently turned into successful implementations by myself and other developers.
- Led a team of five people in the analysis and merging of two previously separate TCL web front-end codebases into a single, more maintainable product.
- Mentored new colleagues and provided pivotal support to the technical lead during the formation of a new team.
- Provided on-site developer support for a major customer website upgrade.
- Worked directly with customers in the statistical analysis and subsequent debugging of games to ensure they met their specifications.

#### 2010 – 2011 DiaCon (Harry Potter Conference)

2010

- Programmed the conference website using PHP, HTML and Javascript, including the registration and payment pages.
- Wrote a responsive web-app for the conference schedule that allowed people to view and favourite programme items. I made use of HTML5's local storage APIs and manifest files to make it work seamlessly both offline and online.
- Helped with the successful planning and running of the event.

#### Mew (Open Source Programming Language)

http://code.google.com/p/mew-lang

• Designed and implemented new language features, test suites and formal specification.

#### 2009 – 2010 Chair of Departmental Student Society, University of York

- Organised and chaired weekly committee meetings.
- Chaired the organisation and running of events.
- Worked to reform the society structure, and therefore achieve ratification from the University of York Students' Union.

## Education

2007–2010	BEng Hons Computer Science, University of York 2:1. Dissertation on Adding Entry-Exit Coverage to Haskell Program Coverage.
2004 - 2007	Orpington College, Bromley, Kent A Levels: Computing — A, Psychology — A, Mathematics — B, English Literature — C

### Personal

I play board games and regularly attend a friend's board games night with my wife. I enjoy going to live stand-up gigs and listen to a number of comedy podcasts.